<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
	<title>Practical Utopians</title>
	<description>The latest content from the Practopians</description>
	<link>http://www.practopians.org</link>
	<atom:link href="http://www.practopians.org/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<language>en-us</language>
	<managingEditor>hbowie@practopians.org (Herb Bowie)</managingEditor>
	<webMaster>hbowie@practopians.org (Herb Bowie)</webMaster>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2018 10:53 PST</lastBuildDate>
	<pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2018 10:53 PST</pubDate>
	<ttl>1440</ttl>
	<item>
		<title>Perspective: Vol 1 Issue 17 - A Broadcast Consciousness</title>
		<link>http://www.practopians.org/perspective/vol-1-issue-17-a-broadcast-consciousness.html</link>
		<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.practopians.org/perspective/vol-1-issue-17-a-broadcast-consciousness.html</guid>
		<pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2018 10:53 PST</pubDate>
		<description>
			
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Basic Info: The Importance of Mission</title>
		<link>http://www.practopians.org/basics/the-importance-of-mission.html</link>
		<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.practopians.org/basics/the-importance-of-mission.html</guid>
		<pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2018 10:53 PST</pubDate>
		<description>
			&lt;p&gt;The dictionary on my Mac defines mission as &amp;ldquo;a strongly felt aim, ambition, or calling.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

			&lt;p&gt;Author: Herb Bowie &lt;/p&gt;
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Quotation: This strange hankering for play and surprise</title>
		<link>http://www.practopians.org/quotes/this-strange-hankering-for-play-and-surprise.html</link>
		<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.practopians.org/quotes/this-strange-hankering-for-play-and-surprise.html</guid>
		<pubDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2018 10:53 PST</pubDate>
		<description>
			&lt;p&gt;That exploratory, expansive drive is what separates delight from demand: when we are in play mode, we are open to new surprises, while our base appetites focus the mind on the urgent needs of staying alive. Understanding that distinction is critical to understanding why play &amp;ndash; despite its seemingly frivolous veneer &amp;ndash; has led to so many important discoveries and innovations. The question of why the &lt;em&gt;Home sapiens&lt;/em&gt; brain possesses this strange hankering for play and surprise is a fascinating one....&lt;/p&gt;

			&lt;p&gt;Author: Steven Johnson &lt;/p&gt;
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Perspective: Vol 1 Issue 16 - The Written Word</title>
		<link>http://www.practopians.org/perspective/vol-1-issue-16-the-written-word.html</link>
		<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.practopians.org/perspective/vol-1-issue-16-the-written-word.html</guid>
		<pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2018 10:53 PST</pubDate>
		<description>
			
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Blog Post: A Broadcast Consciousness</title>
		<link>http://www.practopians.org/blog/hbowie/a-broadcast-consciousness.html</link>
		<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.practopians.org/blog/hbowie/a-broadcast-consciousness.html</guid>
		<pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2018 10:53 PST</pubDate>
		<description>
			&lt;p&gt;Let me take you on a little journey of thought exploring some hitherto unconsidered aspects of our common cultural evolution.&lt;/p&gt;

			&lt;p&gt;Author: Herb Bowie &lt;/p&gt;
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Quotation: Everyone is entitled to his own opinion, but not his own facts</title>
		<link>http://www.practopians.org/quotes/everyone-is-entitled-to-his-own-opinion-but-not-his-own-facts.html</link>
		<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.practopians.org/quotes/everyone-is-entitled-to-his-own-opinion-but-not-his-own-facts.html</guid>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 10:53 PST</pubDate>
		<description>
			&lt;p&gt;Everyone is entitled to his own opinion, but not his own facts&lt;/p&gt;

			&lt;p&gt;Author: Daniel Patrick Moynihan &lt;/p&gt;
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Quotation: It&apos;s sports and it&apos;s all love</title>
		<link>http://www.practopians.org/quotes/its-sports-and-its-all-love.html</link>
		<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.practopians.org/quotes/its-sports-and-its-all-love.html</guid>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 10:53 PST</pubDate>
		<description>
			&lt;p&gt;At the end of the day, it&amp;rsquo;s sports, and it&amp;rsquo;s all love. I feel for both sides. &amp;ndash; Commenting on stopping on the court after a game to console Devin Davis, an opponent who was sobbing on the court, despondent over missing two crucual free throws.&lt;/p&gt;

			&lt;p&gt;Author: Moritz Wagner &lt;/p&gt;
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Quotation: Living with the strains of complexity</title>
		<link>http://www.practopians.org/quotes/living-with-the-strains-of-complexity.html</link>
		<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.practopians.org/quotes/living-with-the-strains-of-complexity.html</guid>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 10:53 PST</pubDate>
		<description>
			&lt;p&gt;Political society wants things simple. Political scientists know them to be complex... One could argue that, in part, the leftist impulse is so conspicuous among the educated and well-to-do precisely because they are exposed to more information, and are accordingly forced to choose between living with the strains of complexity, or lapsing into simplism.&lt;/p&gt;

			&lt;p&gt;Author: Daniel Patrick Moynihan &lt;/p&gt;
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Quotation: Public Truth</title>
		<link>http://www.practopians.org/quotes/public-truth.html</link>
		<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.practopians.org/quotes/public-truth.html</guid>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 10:53 PST</pubDate>
		<description>
			&lt;p&gt;Reviving the common good also depends on each of us taking responsibility for finding, sharing, and insisting upon public truth. By public truth I mean facts about what is happening around us that could affect our well-being, as well as clear logic about the significance of those facts and reasoned analysis about their practical consequences.&lt;/p&gt;

			&lt;p&gt;Author: Robert B. Reich &lt;/p&gt;
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Quotation: Public morality</title>
		<link>http://www.practopians.org/quotes/public-morality.html</link>
		<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.practopians.org/quotes/public-morality.html</guid>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 10:53 PST</pubDate>
		<description>
			&lt;p&gt;Moral guidance about what is right or decent can be found both in religious teachings and in our contemporary understanding of what we owe one another as members of the same society. As I have suggested, they overlap. A public morality that protects our democratic institutions, cherishes the truth, accepts our differences, ensures equal rights and equal opportunity, and invites passionate enagement in our civic life gives our own lives deeper meaning. It enlarges our capacities for attachment and love. It informs our sense of honor and shame. It equips us to be virtuous citizens.&lt;/p&gt;

			&lt;p&gt;Author: Robert B. Reich &lt;/p&gt;
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Quotation: Set off from the rest by a line drawn</title>
		<link>http://www.practopians.org/quotes/set-off-from-the-rest-by-a-line-drawn.html</link>
		<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.practopians.org/quotes/set-off-from-the-rest-by-a-line-drawn.html</guid>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 10:53 PST</pubDate>
		<description>
			&lt;p&gt;Of all dangers to a nation, as things exist in our day, there can be no greater one than having certain portions of the people set off from the rest by a line drawn &amp;ndash; they not privileged as others, but degraded, humiliated, made of no account.&lt;/p&gt;

			&lt;p&gt;Author: Walt Whitman &lt;/p&gt;
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Quotation: That community asks for and gets chaos</title>
		<link>http://www.practopians.org/quotes/that-community-asks-for-and-gets-chaos.html</link>
		<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.practopians.org/quotes/that-community-asks-for-and-gets-chaos.html</guid>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 10:53 PST</pubDate>
		<description>
			&lt;p&gt;From the wild Irish slums of the 19th century Eastern seaboard, to the riot-torn suburbs of Los Angeles, there is one unmistakable lesson in American history; a community that allows a large number of men to grow up in broken families, dominated by women, never acquiring any stable relationship to male authority, never acquiring any set of rational expectations about the future &amp;ndash; that community asks for and gets chaos. Crime, violence, unrest, disorder &amp;ndash; most particularly the furious, unrestrained lashing out at the whole social structure &amp;ndash; that is not only to be expected; it is very near to inevitable. And it is richly deserved.&lt;/p&gt;

			&lt;p&gt;Author: Daniel Patrick Moynihan &lt;/p&gt;
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Quotation: The divine literatus</title>
		<link>http://www.practopians.org/quotes/the-divine-literatus.html</link>
		<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.practopians.org/quotes/the-divine-literatus.html</guid>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 10:53 PST</pubDate>
		<description>
			&lt;p&gt;View&amp;rsquo;d, to-day, from a point of view sufficiently over-arching, the problem of humanity all over the civilized world is social and religious, and is to be finally met and treated by literature. The priest departs, the divine literatus comes. Never was anything more wanted than, to-day, and here in the States, the poet of the modern is wanted, or the great literatus of the modern.&lt;/p&gt;

			&lt;p&gt;Author: Walt Whitman &lt;/p&gt;
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Quotation: The institution of the family</title>
		<link>http://www.practopians.org/quotes/the-institution-of-the-family.html</link>
		<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.practopians.org/quotes/the-institution-of-the-family.html</guid>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 10:53 PST</pubDate>
		<description>
			&lt;p&gt;The institution of the family is decisive in determining not only if a person has the capacity to love another individual but in the larger social sense whether he is capable of loving his fellow men collectively. The whole of society rests on this foundation for stability, understanding and social peace.&lt;/p&gt;

			&lt;p&gt;Author: Daniel Patrick Moynihan &lt;/p&gt;
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Quotation: To differentiate truth from falsehood</title>
		<link>http://www.practopians.org/quotes/to-differentiate-truth-from-falsehood.html</link>
		<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.practopians.org/quotes/to-differentiate-truth-from-falsehood.html</guid>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 10:53 PST</pubDate>
		<description>
			&lt;p&gt;It is the civic responsibility of all of us to check the facts we read or hear, to find and depend upon reliable sources, to share the truth with others, and hold accountable those who lie to us or suppress the truth. We must also ensure that every American has sufficient education to differentiate truth from falsehood, and to think critically about what they read and see.&lt;/p&gt;

			&lt;p&gt;Author: Robert B. Reich &lt;/p&gt;
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Quotation: Man must believe in an open future</title>
		<link>http://www.practopians.org/quotes/man-must-believe-in-an-open-future.html</link>
		<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.practopians.org/quotes/man-must-believe-in-an-open-future.html</guid>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 10:53 PST</pubDate>
		<description>
			&lt;p&gt;Man&amp;rsquo;s freedom is a reality &amp;ndash; a reality that makes a difference to his physical, as well as his mental health. When Frankl&amp;rsquo;s prisoners ceased to believe in the possibility of freedom, they grew sick and died. On the other hand, when they saw that Dachau had no chimney, standing out all night in the rain seemed no great hardship; they laughed and joked. The conclusion needs to be stated in letters ten feet high. In order to realise his possibilities, man must believe in an open future; he must have a vision of something worth doing. And this will not be possible until all the determinism and pessimism that we have inherited from the 19th century &amp;ndash; and which has infected every department of our culture, from poetry to atomic physics &amp;ndash; has been dismissed as fallacious and illogical.&lt;/p&gt;

			&lt;p&gt;Author: Colin Wilson &lt;/p&gt;
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Quotation: Each man is questioned by life</title>
		<link>http://www.practopians.org/quotes/each-man-is-questioned-by-life.html</link>
		<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.practopians.org/quotes/each-man-is-questioned-by-life.html</guid>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 10:53 PST</pubDate>
		<description>
			&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, man should not ask what the meaning of his life is, but rather must recognize that it is he who is asked. In a word, each man is questioned by life; and he can only answer to life by answering for his own life; to life he can only respond by being responsible.&lt;/p&gt;

			&lt;p&gt;Author: Victor Frankl &lt;/p&gt;
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Quotation: Love is the ultimate and the highest goal</title>
		<link>http://www.practopians.org/quotes/love-is-the-ultimate-and-the-highest-goal.html</link>
		<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.practopians.org/quotes/love-is-the-ultimate-and-the-highest-goal.html</guid>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 10:53 PST</pubDate>
		<description>
			&lt;p&gt;A thought transfixed me: for the first time in my life I saw the truth as it is set into song by so many poets, proclaimed as the final wisdom by so many thinkers. The truth &amp;ndash; that love is the ultimate and the highest goal to which man can aspire. Then I grasped the meaning of the greatest secret that human poetry and human thought and belief have to impart: The salvation of man is through love and in love.&lt;/p&gt;

			&lt;p&gt;Author: Victor Frankl &lt;/p&gt;
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Quotation: We should always be fighting evil</title>
		<link>http://www.practopians.org/quotes/we-should-always-be-fighting-evil.html</link>
		<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.practopians.org/quotes/we-should-always-be-fighting-evil.html</guid>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 10:53 PST</pubDate>
		<description>
			&lt;p&gt;All I tried to do in my stories was show that there&amp;rsquo;s some innate goodness in the human condition. And there&amp;rsquo;s always going to be evil; we should always be fighting evil.&lt;/p&gt;

			&lt;p&gt;Author: Stan Lee &lt;/p&gt;
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Quotation: Regulating the ownership of data</title>
		<link>http://www.practopians.org/quotes/regulating-the-ownership-of-data.html</link>
		<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.practopians.org/quotes/regulating-the-ownership-of-data.html</guid>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 10:53 PST</pubDate>
		<description>
			&lt;p&gt;So we had better call upon our lawyers, politicians, philosophers, and even poets to turn their attention to this conundrum: how do you regulate the ownership of data? This may well be the most important political question of our era. If we cannot answer this question soon, our sociopolitical system might collapse.&lt;/p&gt;

			&lt;p&gt;Author: Yuval Noah Harari &lt;/p&gt;
		</description>
	</item>
</channel>
</rss>
